A Guide to the Annie McDonald Hale Sheet Music Collection, 1892-1987
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Annie McDonald Hale Sheet Music Collection 1892-1987
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2010-002
2 containers; 0.6 cu. ft.
A collection of sheet music comprised mostly of popular music from the first half of the twentieth century, including patriotic songs, novelty songs, instrumentals, and show tunes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Annie McDonald Hale Sheet Music Collection was donated to Special Collections in 2008.
Biographical Information
Annie McDonald Hale (1888-1966) was a resident of Blacksburg, Virginia. She was married to Edward A. Hale, owner of Blacksburg's Central Pharmacy.
Scope and Content
This collection contains sheet music collected by Annie McDonald Hale, a Blacksburg, Virginia resident. Additions seem to have been made by Hale's friend, Willie M. Gates, to whom the collection was bequeathed. The collection includes the sheet music for many of the most popular songs of the first half of the twentieth century, though a few items date from the late nineteenth century, and scattered selections dating from the 1960s and 1970s are included as well. Among the selections are patriotic songs, novelty songs, show tunes, instrumentals, and a few pieces that, by later standards, would be considered racially offensive. Many of the pieces feature illustrated covers, some including photographs of the vocalists who made the songs famous.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by name of composition.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Other collections containing sheet music include:
Arthur Lawrie Sheet Music (Ms70-004).
Sheet Music Collection (Ms2003-021).
Ruby Bishop West Collection (Ms86-002).
Separated Material
The following books were removed to be cataloged for the Rare Book Collection:
Kamiki, The New EZ Method for Ukulele and Tiple (New York: Wm. J. Smith, 1952).
Treasure Chest of Songs We Love (New York: Treasure Chest Publications, 1936).
Super Stars of the Golden Era: Collector's Album (Hollywood, CA: Wolf, ca. 1975?).
Contents List
- Aa - Ak (Box-folder 1-1)
  - "Ac-cent-tchu-ate the Positive" - words by Johnny Mercer; music by Harold Arlen (New York: Edwin H. Morris & Company) 1944
  - "Ah! Sweet Mystery of Life" - words by Rida Johnson Young; music by Victor Herbert (New York: M. Witmark & Sons) 1944
- Al (Box-folder 1-2)
  - "Alabama Ball" - words by Wm. Hallen Falls; music by Al W. Beatty (Columbus, Ohio: R. C. Young) 1918
  - "The Alcoholic Blues (Some Blues)" - words by Edward Laska; music by Albert Vontilzer (New York: Broadway Music) 1919
  - "Alexander's Ragtime Band" - words and music by Irving Berlin (New York: ABC Music) 1938
  - "Alice in Wonderland" - words by Bob Hilliard; music by Sammy Fain (New York: Walt Disney Music) 1951
  - "All in the Golden Afternoon" - words by Bob Hilliard; music by Sammy Fain (New York: Walt Disney Music) 1951
  - "(All of a Sudden) My Heart Sings" - words and music by Harold Rome, Jamblan and Herpin (New York: Leeds Music) 1944
  - "All the World Will Be Jealous of Me" - words by Al Dubin; music by Ernest R. Ball (New York: M. Witmark & Sons) 1917
  - "All Through the Day" - words by Oscar Hammerstein II; music by Jerome Kern (New York: Williamson Music) 1946
  - "Along the Navajo Trail" - words and music by Larry Markes, Dick Charles and Eddie De Lange (New York: Leeds Music) 1945
- Am - Az (Box-folder 1-3)
  - "America, Here's My Boy" - words by Andrew B. Sterling; music by Arthur Lange (New York: Joe Morris Music) 1917
  - "Annie's Song" - words and music by John Denver (Greenwich, CT: Cherry Lane Music) 1974
  - "Anywhere I Wander" - words and music by Frank Loesser (New York: Frank Music) 1951
  - "April in Portugal" - words by Jimmy Kennedy (original lyrics by José Galhardo); music by Rauel Ferrão (New York: Chappell & Co.) 1941
  - "Are You From Dixie? ('Cause I'm From Dixie, Too!)" - words by Jack Yellen; music by George L. Cobb (New York: M. Witmark & Sons) 1915
  - "Aren't You Glad You're You" - words by Johnny Burke; music by Jimmy Van Heusen (New York: Burke & Van Heusen) 1945
- Ba - Bh (Box-folder 1-4)
  - "Bali Ha'i" - words by Oscar Hammerstein II; music by Richard Rodgers (New York: Williamson Music) 1949
  - "Battle of Gettysburg: Descriptive March" - music by E. T. Paull (New York: E. T. Paull Music) 1917
  - "Beautiful Eyes" - words by Geo. Whiting and Carter de Haven; music by Ted Snyder (New York: Ted Snyder) 1909
  - "Beautiful Savior: Old Crusader's Hymn" - arranged by Eric Steiner (Rockville Centre, New York: Belwin) 1961
  - "Beg Your Pardon" - words and music by Francis Craig and Beasley Smith (New York: Robbins Music) 1947
  - "The Bells of St. Mary's" - words by Douglas Furber; music by A. Emmett Adams (New York: Chappell & Co.) 1937
  - "Bésame Mucho (Kiss Me Much)" - words by Sunny Skylar (original lyrics by Consuelo Velázquez); music by Consuelo Velázquez (New York: Southern Music Publishing) 1941
  - "The Best Things in Life Are Free" - words and music by B. G. de Sylva, Lew Brown and Ray Henderson (New York: Crawford Music) 1927
- Bi - Bz (Box-folder 1-5)
  - "A Bicycle Built for Two (also known as Daisy Bell)" - words and music by Harry Dacre (Chicago: Calumet Music) 1935
  - "Billy, Billy, Bounce Your Baby Doll" - words by Joe McCarthy; music by Fred Fischer and Al Bryan (New York: Leo. Feist) 1912
  - "Blighty (the Soldier's Home, Sweet Home)" [incomplete] - words and music by R. P. Weston and Bert Lee ([S.l.]: Francis, Day & Hunter) 1916
  - "Blue Moon" - words by Lorenz Hart; music by Richard Rodgers (New York: Robbins Music) 1934
  - "The Boy Scouts' Dream" - words and music by V. Paul Jones (Philadelphia: Jos. Morris) 1915
  - "Buddy" - words by W. C. Polla; music by W. C. Polla (Hartford, CT: C. C. Church) 1919
  - "By Tranquil Waters" - words and music by Ella Ketterer (Philadelphia: Theodore Presser) 1938
- Ca - Cn (Box-folder 1-6)
  - "Candy" - words and music by Mack David, Joan Whitney and Alex Kramer (New York: Leo Feist) 1944
  - "Can't Help Lovin' Dat Man" - words by Oscar Hammerstein II; music by Jerome Kern (Santa Monica, CA: T. B. Harms) c1927
  - "Carbarlick Acid" - by Clarence C. Wiley (New York: Jerome H. Remick) 1907
  - "Careless Hands" - words and music by Bob Hilliard and Carl Sigman (New York: Melrose Music) 1949
  - "Cheek to Cheek" - words and music by Irving Berlin (New York: Irving Berlin) 1935
  - "Chickery Chick" - words by Sylvia Dee; music by Sidney Lippman (New York: Santly-Joy) 1945
  - "Chim Chim Cher-ee" - words and music by Richard M. Sherman and Robert B. Sherman (Burbank, CA: Wonderland Music) 1963
  - "Christmas in Killarney" - words and music by John Redmond, James Cavanaugh and Frank Weldon (New York: Remick Music) 1950
  - "Climb Ev'ry Mountain" - words by Oscar Hammerstein II; music by Richard Rodgers (New York: Williamson Music) 1959
- Co - Cz (Box-folder 1-7)
  - "Come to Baby, Do!" - words and music by Inez James and Sidney Miller (New York: Leeds Music) 1945
  - "Comin' in on a Wing and a Prayer" - words by Harold Adamson; music by Jimmy McHugh (New York: Robbins Music) 1943
  - "Cruising Down the River (on a Sunday Afternoon)" - words and music by Eily Beadell and Nell Tollerton (New York: Henry Spitzer) 1945
  - "Cupid's Wedding Bells" - words by Edward Madden; music by Theodore Morse (New York: F. B. Haviland) 1907
  - "Curiosity Ah!" - words by Jeff T. Branen; music by Malvin Franklin (Chicago: Will Rossiter) 1909
- Da - Dn (Box-folder 1-8)
  - "Daddy Long Legs" - words by Sam M. Lewis and Joe Young; music by Harry Ruby (New York: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder) 1909
  - "Dark Eyes" [cover only] - words by Howard Johnson; music by A. Salami (New York: Robbins Music) n.d.
  - "Day By Day" - words and music by Sammy Cahn, Axel Stordahl, Paul Weston (New York: Barton Music) 1945
  - "Dear Heart" - words by Jean LeFavre; music by W. C. Polla and Willard Goldsmith (Hartford, CT: C. C. Church) 1919
  - "Dear Hearts and Gentle People" - words by Sammy Fain; music by Bob Hilliard (New York: Edwin H. Morris) 1949
  - "Dear Old Wintertime" - words and music by Brown and Remick (New York: Jerome H. Remick) 1910
  - "Deep in the Heart of Texas" - words by June Hershey; music by Don Swander (Hollywood, CA; Melody Lane Publications) 1941
- Do - Dz (Box-folder 1-9)
  - "The Donkey Serenade" - words by Bob Wright and Chet Forrest; music by Rudolf Friml (New York: G. Schirmer) 1937
  - "Don't Fence Me In" - words and music by Cole Porter (New York: Harms) 1944
  - "Don't Let That Moon Get Away" - words by John Burke; music by James V. Monaco (New York: Santly-Joy-Select) 1938
  - "Dreams of the Everyday Housewife" - words and music by Chris Gantry (Nashville, TN: Combine Music) 1968
  - "Dreamy Alabama" - words and music by Mary Earl (New York: Shapiro, Bernstein & Company) 1919
  - "Drifting and Dreaming (Sweet Paradise)" - words by Haven Gillespie; music by Egbert Van Alstyne, Erwin R. Schmidt, Loyal Curtis (New York: Burke & Van Heusen) 1946
  - "The Dublin Rag" - words by Harold Atteridge; music by Phil. Schwartz (New York: Leo. Feist) 1910
- E (Box-folder 1-10)
  - "Ebb Tide" - music by Robert Maxwell (New York: Robbins Music) 1953
  - "Ev-ry Time You'd Do It In A Country Town" - words by Ned Moray; music by Malvin M. Franklin (New York: F. B. Haviland) 1912
  - "Ev'rybody Ought to Know How to Do the Tickle Toe" - words by Otto Harbach; music by Louis A. Hirsch (New York: M. Witmark & Sons) 1917
  - "Ev'rybody Shimmies Now" - words by Eugene West; music by Joe Gold and Edmund J. Porray (New York: Chas. K. Harris) 1918
  - "The Exodus Song" - words by Pat Boone; music by Ernest Gold (New York: Chappell) 1961
- F - G (Box-folder 1-11)
  - "Farewell to the Aloha Oe" [fragment] - words and music by H. M. Queen Liliuokalani (arranged by Jule Bachmann) (Rochester, NY: Lew Berk Music) 1916
  - "Fashion Rag" by Chas. Cohen (Williamsport, PA: Vandersloot Music) 1912
  - "Five Minutes More" - words by Sammy Cahn; music by Jule Styne (New York: Melrose) 1946
  - "For Me and My Gal" - words by Edgar Leslie and E. Ray Goetz; music by Geo. W. Meyer (New York: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder) 1917
  - "Gentle On My Mind" - words and music by John Hartford (Nashville, TN: Glaser Publications) 1967
  - "Give Me the Right to Love You All the While" - words by Ben Bard; music by Abe Glatt (New York: Harry Von Tilzer) 1917
  - "Greensleeves (What Child Is This?)" (traditional) (New York: Larrabee) 1963
- Ha - Hh (Box-folder 1-12)
  - "Hard to Get" - words and music by Jack Segal (New York: M. Witmark & Sons) 1955
  - "Has Anybody Seen My Corinne" - words by Roger Graham; music by Lukie Johnson (New York: Jos. W. Stern) 1918
  - "Hava Nagila" - arranged by Arthur Zepp (Westbury, NY: Pro Art) 1965
  - "Heartaches" - words by John Klenner; music by Al Hoffman (New York: Leeds Music) 1931
  - "He'd Have to Get Under - Get Out and Get Under (to Fix up His Automobile)" - words by Grant Clarke and Edgar Leslie; music by Maurice Abrahams (New York: Maurice Abrahams) 1913
  - "Hey, Look Me Over" - words by Carolyn Leigh; music by Cy Coleman (New York: Morley Music) 1960
- Hi - Hz (Box-folder 1-13)
  - "Hindustan" - words and music by Oliver G. Wallace and Harold Weeks (Chicago: Forster Music) 1918
  - "Hoe Your 'Little Bit' in Your Own Back Yard" - words by Dee Dooling Cahill; music by J. E. Andino (New York: Great Aim Society) 1917
  - "How Soon? (Will I Be Seeing You)" - words by Jack Owens; music by Carroll Lucas (New York: Supreme Music) 1944
  - "How 'Ya Gonna Keep 'Em Down on the Farm (After They've Seen Paree)" - words by Joe Young and Sam M. Lewis; music by Walter Donaldson (New York: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder) 1919
  - "Hush-a-Bye, Ma Baby (the Missouri Waltz)" - words by J. R. Shannon; arranged by Frederic Knight Logan (Chicago: F. J. A. Forster) 1914
- I A - I D (Box-folder 1-14)
  - "I Believe" - words by Sammy Cahn; music by Jule Styne (New York: Sinatra Songs) 1947
  - "I Can't Begin to Tell You" - words by Mack Gordon; music by James V. Monaco (New York: Bregman, Vocco and Conn) 1945
  - "I Don't Know Why" - words by Roy Turn; music by Fred E. Ahlert (New York: Leo Feist) 1946
  - "I Don't Want No Steady Girl" - words by Robert Motley; music by Edward J. Buckley (Trenton, NJ: Trenton Music) 1913
  - "I Don't Want to Walk Without You" - words by Frank Loesser; music by Jule Styne (New York: Paramount Music) 1951
- I E - I Z (Box-folder 1-15)
  - "I Feel Pretty" - words by Stephen Sondheim; music by Leonard Bernstein (New York: G. Schirmer) 1957
  - "I Love My Wife; But, Oh, You Kid!" - words and music by Armstrong and Clark (Chicago: Victor Kremer) 1909
  - "I Love You So Much It Hurts" - words and music by Floyd Tillman (New York: Melody Lane) 1948
  - "I Want Someone to Call Me Dearie" - words by Harry Williams; music by Egbert Van Alstyne (New York: Jerome H. Remick) 1908
  - "I Want to Be Loved Like a Baby" - words and music by William Witol (New York: American Music) 1923
  - "I Wish I Didn't Love You So" - words and music by Frank Loesser (New York: Famous Music) 1947
  - "I Wish I Was In Heaven Sittin' Down" - words and music by Fleta Jan Brown (New York: M. Witmark & Sons) 1908
- Ia - Il (Box-folder 1-16)
  - "I'd Like A Little Loving Now And Then" - words by Earle C. Jones; music by Tom Kelley (New York: Jos. W. Stern) 1907
  - "If You Only Knew What I Know" - words by Jack Caddigan; music by Jas. A. Brennan (Boston: O. E. Story) 1913
  - "If You Talk In Your Sleep Don't Mention My Name" - words by Seymour Brown; music by Nat D. Ayer (New York: Jerome H. Remick) 1911
  - "If Your Wife Wants to Go to the Country, Let Her Go, Let Her Go, Let Her Go" - words by Chas. A. Bayha; music by Harry Jentes (New York: York Music) 1913
  - "I'll Be In My Dixie Home Again To-Morrow" - words and music by Roy Turk and J. Russel Robinson (New York: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder) 1922
  - "I'll Buy That Dream" - words by Herb Magidson; music by Allie Wrubel (New York: Burke and Van Heusen) 1945
- Im (Box-folder 1-17)
  - "I'm Always Chasing Rainbows" - words by Joseph McCarthy; music by Harry Carroll ([S.l.]: Miller Music) 1946
  - "I'm Forever Blowing Bubbles" - words and music by Jaan Kenbrovin and John William Kellette (New York: Jerome H. Remick) 1919
  - "I'm Going To Do What I Please" - words by Alfred Bryan; music by Ted Snyder (New York: Ted Snyder) 1909
  - "I'm Gonna Love That Guy (Like He's Never Been Loved Before)" - words and music by Frances Ash (New York: Bourne) 1945
  - "I'm Looking Over A Four Leaf Clover" - words by Mort Dixon; music by Harry Woods (New York: Remick Music) 1927
- In - Is (Box-folder 1-18)
  - "In A Little Gypsy Tea Room" - words by Edgar Leslie; music by Joe Burke (New York: Joe Morris Music) 1935
  - "In Love In Vain" - words by Leo Robin; music by Jerome Kern (New York: T. B. Harms) 1946
  - "In the Good Old Summer Time" - words by Ren Shields; music by George Evans (New York: Edward B. Marks Music) 1949
  - "In the Hills of Old Kentucky (My Mountain Rose)" - words by J. R. Shannon; music by Chas. L. Johnson (Chicago: F. J. A. Forster) 1914
  - "In the Middle of May" - words and music by Fred E. Ahlert and Al Stillman (New York: Crawford Music) 1945
  - "In the Shade of the New Apple Tree" - words by E. Y. Harburg; music by Harold Arlen (New York: Chappell) 1938
  - "Indian Love Call" - words by Otto Harbach and Oscar Hammerstein II; music by Rudolf Friml (New York: Harms) 1924
  - "The Island of Roses and Love" - words by Earle C. Jones; music by Neil Moret (New York: Jerome H. Remick) 1911
  - "Isle of Capri" - words by Jimmy Kennedy; music by Will Grosz (New York: T. B. Harms) 1934
- It - Iz (Box-folder 1-19)
  - "It Might As Well Be Spring" - words by Oscar Hammerstein II; music by Richard Rodgers (New York: Williamson Music) 1945
  - "It's A Long, Long Way to Tipperary" - words and music by Jack Judge and Harry Williams (London: B. Feldman) 1912
  - "It's Been A Long, Long Time" - words by Sammy Cahn; music by Jule Styne (New York: Edwin H. Morris) 1945
  - "It's Nice, to Be Nice, to a Nice Little Girl Like You" - words by Will A. Hellan; music by Seymour Furth (New York: Jos. Morris) 1910
  - "It's the Same Old Dream" - words by Sammy Kahn; music by Jule Styne (New York: Sinatra Songs) 1947
  - "I've Been Working on the Railroad" - arranged by Nick Manoloff (Chicago: Calumet Music) 1936
  - "I've Found the Nesting Place of the Bluebird" - words by Jack Yellen; music by Abe Olman (New York: Henry Burr Music) 1919
  - "I've Got a Pocketful of Dreams" - words by John Burke; music by James V. Monaco (New York: Santly-Joy-Select) 1938
  - "I've Lost You So Why Should I Care" - words and music by Richard Howard (Boston: Daly) 1916
- J - K (Box-folder 1-20)
  - "Just a Baby's Prayer at Twilight" - words by Sam M. Lewis and Joe Young; music by M. K. Jerome (New York: Waterson, Berlin & Snyder) 1918
  - "Just a Little Bit South of North Carolina" [incomplete] - words and music by Sonny Skyler, Bette Cannon, Arthur Shaftel (New York: Porgie, Debin & Friedman) 1941
  - "Just a Prayer Away" - words by Charles Tobias; music by David Kapp (New York: Shapiro, Bernstein & Company) 1944
  - "K-K-K-Katy" - words and music by Geoffrey O'Hara (New York: Leo. Feist) 1918
  - "Kiss Me Good Night (Out the Window You Must Go)" - words and music by Lew Brown and Joe Goodwin (New York: Leo. Feist) 1913
- L (Box-folder 2-1)
  - "The Last Round-Up" - words and music by Billy Hill (New York: Shapiro, Bernstein & Company) 1933
  - "Laughing on the Outside (Crying on the Inside)" - words by Ben Raleigh; music by Bernie Wayne (New York: Broadcast Music) 1946
  - "Lazy River" - words and music by Hoagy Carmichael and Sidney Arodin (New York: Peer International) 1958
  - "Let It Snow! Let It Snow! Let It Snow!" - words by Sammy Cahn; music by Jule Styne (New York: Edwin H. Morris) 1945
  - "Let's Go to Church (Next Sunday Morning)" - words and music by Steve Allen (New York: Beechwood Music) 1950
  - "Lilacs in the Rain" [incomplete] - words by Mitchell Parish; music by Peter De Rose (New York: Robbins Music) [1939?]
  - "Little Old Lady" - words and music by Hoagy Carmichael and Stanley Adams (New York: Chappell) 1936
  - "Look At Me (Bing) (Bang) I'm the Guy" - words and music by Clarence Gaskill and Charles Shisler (Philadelphia: Emmett J. Welch) 1912
  - "The Loveliest Night of the Year" - words by Paul Francis Webster; music by Juventino Rosas; adapted by Irving Aaronson (New York: Robbins Music) 1951
  - "Loyalty Is the Word Today, Loyalty to the U.S.A." - words by Dee Dooling Cahill; music by J. E. Andino (New York: Great Aim Society) 1917
- Ma - Mx (Box-folder 2-2)
  - "Mack the Knife"- words by Marc Blitzstein (original German words by Bet Brecht); music by Kurt Weill (New York: Harms) 1955
  - "Mam'selle" - words by Mack Gordon; music by Edmund Goulding (New York: Leo Feist) 1947
  - "Melody of Love" - words by Tom Glazer; music by H. Engelmann (New York: Shapiro, Bernstein & Company) 1954
  - "Memory" - words by Trevor Nunn, after T. S. Eliot; music by Andrew Lloyd Webber (Winona, MN: Hal Leonard) 1981
  - "Michelle" - words and music by John Lennon and Paul McCartney (New York: Maclen Music) 1965
  - "Mister Gallagher and Mister Shean" - [words and music by Al Shean and Ed. Gallagher] (New York: Jack Mills) 1922
  - "Monkey Weasel Boogie Woogie" - by David Carr Glover (Rockville Centre, New York: Belwin) 1967
- My A - My P (Box-folder 2-3)
  - "My Aviator Girl" - words by Geo. W. Jeffords; music by M. L. Jeffords (New York: Columbia Music) 1917
  - "My Blue Heaven" [incomplete] - words by George Whiting; music by Walter Donaldson (New York: Leo. Feist) [1927?]
  - "My Dream of You" - words by Henry Vaughan; music by Paul Rodney (New York: Boosey) c1895
  - "My Dreams Are Getting Better All the Time" - words by Mann Curtis; music by Vic Mizzy (New York: Santly-Joy) 1944
  - "My Favorite Things" - words by Oscar Hammerstein II; music by Richard Rodgers (New York: Williamson Music) 1959
  - "My Happiness" - words by Betty Peterson; music by Borney Bergantine (Kansas City, MO: Blasco Music) 1948
  - "My Little Girl" - words by Sam M. Lewis and Will Dillon; music by Albert Von Tilzer (New York: Broadway Music) 1916
  - "My Little Honey Bee" - words by Arthur Longbrake; music by Max S. Witt (New York: Jos. Morris) 1909
  - "My Prayer" - words and musical adaptation by Jimmy Kennedy; music by Georges Boulanger (New York: Shapiro, Bernstein & Company) 1939
- My Q - My Z (Box-folder 2-4)
  - "My Queen in the Kingdom of Love" - words by Wm. A. Downs; music by Tom Mayo Geory (Chicago: Harold Rossiter Music) 1915
  - "My Sister and I" [incomplete] - words and music by Hy Zaret, Joan Whitney and Alex Kramer (New York: Broadcast Music) 1941
  - "My Wife's Gone to the Country (Hurrah! Hurrah!)" [incomplete] - words by Geo. Whiting and Irving Berlin; music by Ted Snyder (New York: Ted Snyder) 1909
  - "My Wild Irish Rose" - words and music by Chauncey Olcott (New York: M. Witmark & Sons) 1899
  - "My Wild Irish Rose" - words and music by Chauncey Olcott (New York: M. Witmark & Sons) 1918
- N (Box-folder 2-5)
  - "Narcissus" - by Ethelbert Nevin (Boston: Boston Music) c1899
  - "Naughty Eyes" - words by Harry Sylvester; music by Percy Wenrich (New York: Jerome H. Remick) 1908
  - "Now is the Hour (Maori Farewell Song)" - words and music by Maewa Kaihan, Clement Scott, Dorothy Stewart (New York: Leeds Music) 1946
- O (Box-folder 2-6)
  - "Oh Johnny, Oh Johnny, Oh!" - words by Ed. Rose; music by A. Olman (Chicago: Forster Music) c1917
  - "Oh! What I Know About You" - words and music by Jos. H. McKeon, Harry M. Piano, W. Raymond Walker (New York: Harry Von Tilzer) 1909
  - "The Old Apple Tree" - words by Jack Scholl; music by M. K. Jerome (New York: M. Witmark & Sons) 1938
  - "The Old Lamp-Lighter" - words by Charles Tobias; music by Nat Simon (New York: Shapiro, Bernstein & Company) 1946
  - "On the Atchison, Topeka and the Santa Fe" - words by Johnny Mercer; music by Harry Warren (New York: Leo Feist) 1945
  - "On the Road to Mandalay" - adapted from "Barrack-Room Ballads" by Rudyard Kipling;; music by Oley Speaks (New York: G. Schirmer) 1907
  - "On With Roanoke" - by G. V. Kromer (Roanoke, VA: G. V. Kromer) 1950
  - "One Dozen Roses" - words by Roger Lewis and Country Washburn; music by Dick Jurgens and Walter Donavan (New York: Famous Music) 1942
  - "Over There" - words and music by George M. Cohan (New York: William Jerome) 1917
- P (Box-folder 2-7)
  - "Pack Up Your Troubles in Your Old Kit Bag and Smile, Smile, Smile!" - words by George Asaf; music by Felix Powell (New York: Chappell, T. B. Harms) 1915
  - "Pal of Mine" - words by Bartley C. Costello; music by J. S. Nathan (New York: Leo. Feist) 1905
  - "Pass Me By" - words by Carolyn Leigh; music by Cy Coleman (New York: Edwin H. Morris) 1964
  - "Powder Your Face With Sunshine (Smile! Smile! Smile!)" - words and music by Carmen Lombardo and Stanley Rochinski (New York: Lombardo Music) 1948
  - "Pretty Baby" - words by Gus Kahn; music by Tony Jackson and Egbert Van Alstyne (New York: Jerome H. Remick) 1916
  - "(Put Another Nickel in) Music! Music! Music!" - words and music by Stephan Weiss and Bernie Baum (New York: Cromwell) 1950
  - "Put on Your Old Grey Bonnett" - words by Stanley Murphy; music by Percy Wenrich (New York: Jerome H. Remick) 1909
- R (Box-folder 2-8)
  - "Raindrops Keep Fallin' on My Head" - words by Hal David; music by Burt Bacharach (New York: Blue Seas Music) 1969
  - "Red Onion Rag" - by Abe Oleman (New York: Geo. W. Meyer Music) 1912